<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christian Warmuth</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Christian Warmuth</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our second online course</title><link>/post/openhpi_2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/openhpi_2/</guid><description>Motivation &amp;amp; feedback from the previous course: Together with Johannes Hötter, our first online course on openHPI around the topics of &amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for beginners&amp;rdquo; reached over 15,800 learners (as of June 2022). In a previous blog post, I reflected on the experience of conceptualizing, recording, and hosting our first online course.
At the end of the previous course, we tried to understand how the participants perceived the course, how we could improve, which questions were still open, and if participants wished for a continuation.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Graphs</title><link>/post/knowledge_graph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/knowledge_graph/</guid><description>Abstract: In a project with the Wildenstein Plattner Institute in New York, we worked on constructing a knowledge graph based on art-historical documents. The goal is to create a graph-based representation of the relationships between different artworks, artists, and historical events and use this representation to gain insights and use this representation for downstream applications and analysis.
Setting: The project described in the following was conducted as part of a lecture/seminar called &amp;ldquo;Knowledge Graphs&amp;rdquo; as part of my master&amp;rsquo;s degree at HPI together with Konstantin Dobler and Malte Barth.</description></item><item><title>Software Benchmarking</title><link>/post/software_benchmarking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/software_benchmarking/</guid><description>Abstract: In 2020, on GitHub, more than 60 million new repositories were created by over 56 million users1. There is a common understanding of the code base for hobby-project repositories or small-scale projects with few developers. Its &amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo; is relatively easy to attain and capture. However, the bigger software projects become and the more complex they become, the more management and oversight might help ensure code maturity and health. Especially large code bases impose new challenges and open up new opportunities for the automated analysis and visualization of the software data.</description></item><item><title>Hospital Discharge Location Prediction</title><link>/post/discharge_location_prediction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/discharge_location_prediction/</guid><description>Abstract: Heart failure is one of the leading causes of hospitalization and rehospitalization in American hospitals, leading to high expenditures and increased medical risk for patients. The discharge location has a strong association with the risk of rehospitalization and mortality, which makes determining the most suitable discharge location for a patient a crucial task. So far, work regarding patient discharge classification is limited to the state of the patients at the end of the treatment, including statistical analysis and machine learning.</description></item><item><title>Our own online course on AI with 15k+ participants</title><link>/post/openhpi_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/openhpi_1/</guid><description>COVID has fundamentally changed how we work and learn in a few weeks only - everything is now digital. Therefore, it was a great pleasure to create, record, and host our free online course on &amp;gt;Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Beginners&amp;lt; on openHPI. A project together with my fellow student and friend - Johannes Hötter.
With our online course on openHPI we have already reached over 15,800 learners and reached an average of 4.</description></item><item><title>Neurodesign &amp; Eyetracking research</title><link>/post/eyetracking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/eyetracking/</guid><description>Abstract: Eyetracking has recently gained a lot of attention and has also found a way into consumer products like modern laptops 1. The aim of this explorative research was to use an eyetracker to analyze different behavioral patterns over longer periods for two participants without creating laboratory conditions. This setup was consciously chosen so that we could test the robustness of our assertions under natural conditions. Here, we analyzed the pupil diameter, the position on the screen, and the position of the head relative to the display while recording which software applications the participants used and event data for the respective applications.</description></item></channel></rss>